// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Who invented Java Programming?",
    answer: "James Gosling",
    options: [
      "Guido van Rossum",
      "James Gosling",
      "Dennis Ritchie",
      "Bjarne Stroustrup"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which statement is true about Java?",
    answer: "Java is a platform-independent programming language",
    options: [
      "Java is a sequence-dependent programming language",
      "Java is a code dependent programming language",
      " Java is a platform-dependent programming language",
      "Java is a platform-independent programming language"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?",
    answer: "JDK",
    options: [
      "JRE",
      "JIT",
      "JDK",
      "JVM"
      ]
      
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which one of the following is not a Java feature?",
    answer: "Use of pointers",
    options: [
      "Object-oriented",
      "Use of pointers",
      "Portable",
      "Dynamic and Extensible"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: " Which of these cannot be used for a variable name in Java?",
    answer: "keyword",
    options: [
      "identifier & keyword",
      "identifier",
      "keyword",
      "none of the mentioned"
    ]
  },
   {
     numb: 6,
     question: "What is the extension of java code files?",
     answer: ".java",
     options: [
       ".js",
       ".txt",
       ".class",
       ".java"
     ]
   },
    {
     numb: 7,
     question: " Which environment variable is used to set the java path?",
     answer: "JAVA_HOME",
     options: [
       "MAVEN_Path",
       "JavaPATH",
       "JAVA",
       "JAVA_HOME"
     ]
   },
   {
     numb: 8,
     question: "Which of the following is not an OOPS concept in Java?",
     answer: "Compilation",
     options: [
       "Polymorphism",
       "Inheritance",
       "Compilation",
       "Encapsulation"
     ]
   },
  {
     numb: 9,
     question: "What is not the use of “this” keyword in Java?",
     answer: "Passing itself to the method of the same class",
     options: [
       "Referring to the instance variable when a local variable has the same name",
       "Passing itself to the method of the same class",
       "Passing itself to another method",
       "Calling another constructor in constructor chaining"
     ]
   },
   {
     numb: 10,
     question: "Which of the following is a type of polymorphism in Java Programming?",
     answer: "Compile time polymorphism",
     options: [
       "Multiple polymorphism",
       "Compile time polymorphism",
       "Multilevel polymorphism",
       "Execution time polymorphism"
     ]
   },
];